And no one sings me lullabies. And no one makes me close my eyes.
Pink Floyd: Live at Pompeii is a music,
documentary film directed by Adrian Maben.
British progressive rock band Pink Floyd perform at the ancient Roman
Amphitheater in the ruins of Pompeii, Italy in 1971.
Although the band perform a typical live set from the era,
there is no audience beyond the basic film crew.
Self - Bass, Vocals, played by Roger Waters.
Self - Guitar, Vocals, played by David Gilmour.
Self - Keyboard, Backing Vocals, played by Richard Wright.
Self - Drums, played by Nick Mason.
Pink Floyd: Live at Pompeii is a 1972 concert film directed by Adrian Maben with the English rock
band Pink Floyd performing at the ancient Roman amphitheatre in Pompeii, Italy.
The band performs a typical live set from the era, but there
is no audience beyond the basic film crew.
The main footage in and around the amphitheatre was filmed over four days in October 1971, using the band's regular touring
equipment, including a mobile 8-track recorder from Paris (before being bumped up to 16-track in post-production).
Additional footage filmed in a Paris television studio the following
December was added for the original 1972 release.
The film was then re-released in 1974 with additional studio material of the band
working on The Dark Side of the Moon, and interviews at Abbey Road Studios.
The film has subsequently been released on video numerous times, and in 2002, a director's cut was released on DVD, which combined
the original footage from 1971 with more contemporary shots of space and the area around Pompeii, assembled by Maben.
In April 2025, a 4K restoration, Pink Floyd at Pompeii – MCMLXXII, was shown in cinemas by
Trafalgar Releasing and Sony Music Vision, and released on home media shortly after.
This was followed by an album with the remixed songs and outtakes, which was
released on 2 May 2025 and topped the music charts in several countries.
A number of bands have taken inspiration from the film in creating
their own videos, or filming concerts without an audience.
The film explores themes of concert, rock 'n' roll,
concert film, progressive rock, pompeii.